<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Github on Rafael Widjajahakim - Sample Works</title><link>https://raffwh.github.io/tags/github/</link><description>Recent content in Github on Rafael Widjajahakim - Sample Works</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://raffwh.github.io/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hello World of Website Building</title><link>https://raffwh.github.io/p/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://raffwh.github.io/p/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://raffwh.github.io/p/hello-world/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hello World of Website Building" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="background-story"&gt;BACKGROUND STORY
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creating a portfolio website has been a personal project todolist for so many years.
But, there were a lot of obstacles (mostly personal motivations) to clearly make one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more legit reasons are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As many typical website builders (Wix, Squarespace, etc.) will require cost to host, which one is worth it to try for my very early stage build? Most of these are for eCommerce, and I don&amp;rsquo;t need many of these tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there a pre-made theme among these websites that fit to my need?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to organize the website for what I can present/provide? I am not in Art &amp;amp; Design field where I have many pictures or showcase products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-more-advanced-path-why-run-before-walk"&gt;A MORE ADVANCED PATH (why run before walk)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometime ago, I found portfolio website from someone in tech. The theme was not what I have seen in common website builders.
At the footer of the page, it says &amp;lsquo;Built with Hugo, through Netlify&amp;quot;.
At that time, I have not coded with Python, Linux, or anything. I was not even familiar with Github etc.
I just want to use that theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I tried to follow any articles I could find.
But I could not finish testing and got a job that was not that technical anyway.
So I thought, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need it anyway; so I stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="now"&gt;NOW
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward, I found out that Github can host a simple static website through the pages.
So, I guess it is time to finally check that todolist&amp;hellip; except,&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="more-headache"&gt;MORE HEADACHE
&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;!--- Wrap text ---&gt;
&lt;!-- Wrap text --&gt;
&lt;!--# comment --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{::comment}comment {:/comment}&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>